# Michael Stainsbury | Dev Ops Engineer

Location: Orpington, London, BR6 0QL

Telephone: 07957 324315

Email: michael.stainsbury@gmail.com

#### **Professional Profile**

I am an AWS Certified Solutions Architect and Developer, Team Leading Cloud projects at BAE Systems. I am also an experienced Application Support Engineer Team Lead with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in AWS, JavaScript, Java, SQL, Technical Support and Agile. I am a strong engineering professional with an MSc in Data Communication Systems from Brunel University and I am a member of the British Computer Society.

### IT / Technical skills

AWS CloudFormation, Ansible	SQL, Oracle
AWS EC2, S3, IAM	Python
AWS Lambda, Step Functions	☐ Java
AWS DynamoDB, RDS	JavaScript
Azure Virtual Machines	☐ Git
Azure Storage Accounts	☐ Terraform
Azure Data Factory	Visual Studio Code

#### Career Highlights

I started the last phase of a Data Transformation project having committed to demonstrating Azure Data Factory even though my experience was with AWS. I rapidly up-skilled in ADF and requested a Corporate Azure environment. I tested the environment to ensure that all the basic activities I could do in AWS could also be done in Azure. I guided my colleague, a Data Scientist, in how to use the new environment. I developed new features in Azure Data Factory to process data. We presented our findings to the client. The client was so pleased with our results that they asked us to pitch for an unexpected fourth phase!

I was the Team Lead of a team of five recent graduates tasked with installing Openshift, an enterprise Kubernettes application platform, to test applications prior to release. Nobody in the team or in the department had experience of Openshift. I immediately tasked the team with upskilling in Openshift. I divided the installation into work tasks and had each task investigated. We incrementally worked through each task until we had a successful installation. The result was a fully working Openshift installation which is used by the whole department.

NetReveal is a complex system that takes a long time to install. To speed up problem resolution I installed the supported versions of NetReveal on AWS EC2 instances and backed them up to AMI images. This allowed problems to be reproduced rapidly from images that always had clean data.

## **Career History**

**December 2018 - Present** 

BAES Systems AI, London DevOps Engineer

I investigated the use of AWS for data transformation and processing. The project was managed

#### Michael Stainsbury | Dev Ops Engineer

using the "lean start up" methodology. I used AWS Glue, Amazon Athena, Amazon Elastic Map Reduce, S3, EC2, Lambda, Step Functions. My major contribution was with automation using AWS CloudFormation and Ansible to provision EC2 instances.

In the project's third phase and we have pivoted to use Azure Data Factory. To support this I have upskilled to be able to manage Azure cloud services including Azure Virtual Machines and Azure Storage Accounts. The project is now in it's fourth phase and I am using Terraform to rapidly provision Azure processing environments.

I was a Tech Lead leading a team of four Engineers. The purpose of this project was to install Openshift, Red Hat's version of Kubernetes with Docker. I developed the Cloudformation and Ansible scripts to automate the installation.

I was a Scrum Master and Lead Engineer leading a small teams of four Engineers. The project is JavaScript (React and Node) in an AWS environment. Skills used include AWS SDK and Lambda, Networking (VPCs). The purpose of the project was to enable the rapid provisioning of VPC environments.

#### December 2008 - December 2018

BAES Systems AI, Guildford Engineer

I was the NetReveal Service Desk lead and have one colleague reporting to me. As a member of the software engineering team I act as the interface between Engineering and our existing customers via Customer Support. I also provide support to Project Teams installing new systems.

I was responsible for the triage of new issues and managing the prioritisation of new issues. Manage the life cycle of an issue from first receipt through to closure and follow up actions. I would manage communication with the caller, setting their expectations and maintaining two way communication throughout the process. I would Investigate java Oracle issues using IntelliJ and Oracle SQL in an AWS environment I was responsible for issuing NetReveal software licenses.

May 2002 – Dec 2008 Ford Motor Company - Developer ASP, HTML, MS Access, Java, JSP, Oracle May 2001 - May 2002 Procomsoft - Developer Java, XML Jan 2001 – Mar 2001 Ford Motor Company - Developer ASP, HTML, MS Access, Oracle Nov 2000 – Dec 2000 Intrustworld.com - Developer Visual Basic, SQL Server, XML Mar 1999 – Nov 2000 Logica at Ford Motor Company - Developer Cool:gen, Cobol, DB2 Sep 1998 – Mar 1999 EDS at Xerox - Developer Cobol, DB2 May 1995 – Sep 1998 NatWest Bank - Analyst Programer Cobol, DB2 Sep 1993 – May 1995 Safeway Stores (now Morrisons) - Analyst Programer SAS Feb 1993 – Aug 1993 **Blackpool Health Authority - Assistant Network Technician** 

## **Education and qualifications**

AWS Certified Developer Associate - Amazon Web Services - 2019
AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate - Amazon Web Services - 2018
ITIL V3 foundation certificate
Member of the British Computer Society, MBCS CITP
BCS Professional Exams, equivalent to 2:2 BSc – British Computer Society - 1999
Data Communication Systems, MSc – Brunel University - 1994
Microbiology and Virology, BSc – Warwick University - 1990